Zhang Haiqi!
You can't escape!
[Archives: The Nanyang Mystery]
[Episode 15]
[Southern Archives]
These are the secret symbols used
by Archives agents during collaborations.
Different symbols mean different things.
Memorize them before sunset.
[To warn one not to enter what's ahead;
there's danger.]
[Wealth] [Material success] [Begin]
[Power] [Health] [Courage]
What's the point of learning this?
Isn't being strong enough?
I'd rather spend this time training.
What?
But you must remember
at least this one symbol.
This symbol represents danger.
It represents the highest level
of danger in the Archives.
If you ever, in future missions,
encounter this symbol,
leave immediately—
don't hesitate.
Because it means
no agent can ever return from there alive.
District 13
of Xiacheng Underground Waters.
Southeast entrance
of the unknown ancient ruins.
Third exploration.
Mission objective:
collect antidote materials.
Five explorers in total.
Dived 15 zhang,
about 50 meters.
Zhang Nanshan, Zhang Dahai.
[Fireworks; Fireworks;
There are fireworks below.]
There are fireworks below.
Fireworks?
[20 minutes left to save Shrimpie]
Shrimpie...
Wait for me.
I will definitely save your life.
Shrimpie.
Wait for me.
Now you know.
You are just a mortal.
Yet you really thought you were a god.
Zhang Haiqi.
What is your plan with Mo Yungao?
Zhang Haiqi...
The file the Commander wants
is in the deepest part.
Fireworks. There are fireworks below.
[Fireworks; Fireworks;
There are fireworks below.]
I gave you some life-saving medicine.
You won't die anytime soon.
Where are we?
The outer passage.
It's safe for now.
How did you get in?
The Archives has
a self-destruct defense system.
If someone enters the Archives
and opens the Broken Dragon Stone
from the inside,
the underground will connect,
and seawater will immediately pour in,
flooding the entire Archives.
Ordinary people wouldn't survive,
but I can dive over.
In a little while,
the entire Archives will be flooded.
Then, after getting the medicine,
we can swim out.
Are you pretending not to understand
or not to hear me?
I said you failed.
You can't get that thing,
and you can't save Zhang Haixia.
When he was alive,
you didn't change your bad habits.
Now you regret it.
Who are you throwing this tantrum for?
Then just let me die here.
There is one last way.
Come with me.
It will be another 6 hours
before the tide ebbs.
Those jellyfish will recede with the tide
and leave that sea area.
As long as we go down again
before the tide ebbs,
there's still a chance.
Where are we going now?
I'll show you the truth
about the Southern Archives.
Aren't we supposed to save Shrimpie?
If you want to save him,
you must first understand
the truth of the Archives.
Those things
are not so pleasant to look at.
As a normal person,
it will be hard to understand
after seeing them,
and you might even break down.
I think I can handle it.
I know what you're thinking.
A normal person
who has done some extraordinary things
always thinks they are no longer mortal.
Over this long period of time,
I have seen too many of them.
This is not human skin, is it?
Of course not.
These are all made of animal skin
to record the ancient tattoos
of a family.
The Zhang family.
The Zhang family?
Yes. To understand
the origin of the Archives,
we must start with the Zhang family.
In the north of our country,
there was a Zhang family
[Zhang]
who lived deep in the mountains
and did a special kind of business.
This family line was passed down for a long time.
The Zhang family had a culture
of getting tattoos on their bodies.
The tattoo recorded on this piece of skin
has a history of thousands of years.
Thousands of years...
Legend has it that over 1,000 years ago,
the Zhang family established
the Southern Archives.
to specifically investigate
strange events in the western region.
Later, Archives were established
in various places.
The Southern Archives
was established the latest,
with a history of just over 80 years.
The Zhang family sure sticks their noses
into a lot of things.
They don't care
even about the Empress Dowager.
Is there no farm work
to do in their village?
But in actuality,
the Archives were a medium of cooperation
between the Zhang family
and the imperial court.
The imperial court
allocated a lot of money
for the Archives
to eliminate the bad and protect the good,
and investigate mysterious incidents
across the land.
After all the changes in the world,
the Archives survived.
By investigating these events,
we can earn a lot of income.
So the Archives
became our livelihood.
So that's how the Archives came to be.
That Nanyang Maritime Supervisory Office
and its secret branch,
they weren't completely fooling me.
When the Archives were first established,
only the Zhang family members
were involved.
But since the last century,
the Zhang family's population
has decreased.
So in the remote Nanyang region,
we started recruiting orphans.
Just like Shrimpie and me.
Right.
We made you all
change your surnames to Zhang
and trained you
to become members of the Archives.
This time,
I will let you know
what the Zhang family truly is.
This way.
Zhang Ruipu?
Why is his body here?
I brought him back from the Nan'an.
I've placed him here for now.
Take a look
and see if there's anything special.
His fingers are very long.
I noticed this before.
It's one of the characteristics
of the Zhang family.
Through special training,
their fingers become longer
than ordinary people's.
These long fingers
are used to decipher mechanisms.
The longer the fingers,
the better they can reach
into narrower spaces.
Zhang Ruipu's file.
This was taken
when the Minister of Commerce
was negotiating with foreigners.
[Southern Archives]
[Case closure report]
Zhang Ruipu, Minister of Commerce.
Ninety years ago.
He was in his 20s back then.
Now he is over 100?
I saw in other documents at the Archives
that the Zhang family members...
live quite long.
But I didn't expect them
to live this long.
They do live longer than ordinary people.
Besides long fingers and longevity,
the Zhang family members
also all have tattoos.
The ink
is made from special herbs and bird blood
mixed together.
They only appear when the blood is hot.
This is a rubbing of his tattoo,
used to verify his identity.
Because everyone's tattoo is different.
The herbs used for the tattoo
are very rare
and have unique effects.
They can make
the Zhang family's skills and physique
surpass those of ordinary people.
They will die slower.
At the same time, it makes our blood
different from ordinary people's.
Shrimpie and I are both adopted orphans,
but he has a tattoo and I don't.
Because you're not
a real Zhang family member yet.
Let's go.
Mentor,
how did your wound heal so fast?
Because the hot springs here
and Zhang family blood
can help them heal quickly.
You and Shrimpie
are both from the Zhang family.
Only I'm not.
Come here.
We have been apart for 10 years.
After these 10 years of experience,
It's time for you to grow up.
Mentor, why am I feeling a bit dizzy?
The hot spring here is very special.
Ordinary people can't last long in it.
Mentor...
Then what are you going to do?
You have planted your own cause.
Now, the chance
I originally wanted to give you to leave
is also gone.
Then,
you can only accept your own fate.
From this day forth,
you shall offer your body
to feed the blood.
When the blood boils,
it shall be unleashed.
Thus, you shall stand firm
in the Primordial World,
and nothing shall be denied to you.
Zhang Hailou.
From now on,
you are a member of the Zhang family.
Is this what it feels like
to be a member of the Zhang family?
This is so cool.
I clearly felt like
I was going to die just now.
But now I feel like I can do it again.
Because the pigment I told you about
is made from rare and expensive herbs
mixed together.
These herbs
have excellent healing
and pain-relieving effects.
So you'll feel like
you're recovering very quickly.
Furthermore, these medicines
will improve your physical functions
to some extent.
You'll gain strength
greater than an ordinary person's.
Go.
I got the medicine.
But isn't the duration of being a Zhang
a bit too short?
It's not a miracle drug.
Your body needs time to adapt.
You take the medicine first
and go save Shrimpie.
I'll be right behind you.
We've delayed for too long.
This medicine wasn't easy to get.
Zhang Haixia.
Answer whatever I ask.
Where am I?
Th-This is
the Dong family's villa.
The Dong family's villa?
Y-Yes.
Who brought me here?
M-Miss Dong.
Miss Dong.
Miss Dong?
Yes.
You shall offer your body
to feed the blood.
When the blood boils,
it shall be unleashed.
Thus, you shall stand firm
in the Primordial World,
and nothing shall be denied to you.
Mentor.
Miss Dong said
you were injured,
and asked us to take good care of you.
Did she bring back another man?
Yes, there is another man.
He is already awake.
Where is he?
Miss Dong is taking care of him herself.
Where is Miss Dong?
I-In the courtyard.
That old roof beam was just repaired.
If you break it,
I'll use you to patch it up.
Your disciple hasn't recovered yet,
and you don't even care.
At your age,
can't you learn how to care for others?
You didn't die, did you?
How are you feeling?
It feels great
to be a member of the Zhang family.
I just feel
like I missed out a lot
over the past decade.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
You almost died.
Go lie back down.
Why would I?
Where is Shrimpie?
He's saved.
He woke up a few days earlier than you.
You never do anything right,
but you finally
did something right this time.
Where is he?
At this hour,
it should be the same as usual.
Brat.
He hasn't changed his bad habits at all.